STEPHANIE MONSON

M: 715-225-0882 • 1848 St. Clair Ave. St. Paul, MN 55105 stefanimonson@gmail.com • stefanimonson.info

COMPUTER PROGRAMMER/ANALYST

As a computer programmer with 6+ years of experience in developing and maintaining applications and databases, I am seeking an opportunity to use my skills in creating, designing, and implementing programs that will assist in making the lives of others easier. I have been promoted to higher level technology-related positions at every permanent job, demonstrating my commitment to excellence and hard work in the workplace. Knowing that I have created applications that allow for more efficient work flow and data management is both my greatest motivation and reward.

Core Programming Languages Include:

C++ • CSS • HTML • Java • JavaScript • PHP • PROGRESS • SQL • VB • VB.Net • XML

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Computer Programmer

Oct. 2017 - April 2018

Developed applications that assist in wiping hard drives and automating computer installations for Windows, Linux and macOS. (PCS FOR PEOPLE • St. Paul, MN)

- Developed applications in both Visual Basic 2017 and Java to assist automatic installations of programs for Windows, Linux Mint 18.3 (Serena) and macOS 10.12 (Sierra)
- Created secure solid state drive erasure application in accordance with National Association for Information Destruction standards
- Created automated scripts in both shell and batch
- Implemented JSON and SOAP web communications using Java
- Trained new repair technicians in the diagnosis, repair and refurbishment of computers
- Continued to perform duties from previous position in new role

Repair Technician Feb.2016 – Oct. 2017

Diagnosed, repaired and refurbished computers for low-income households. (PCS FOR PEOPLE ● St. Paul, MN)

- Installed operating system, useful applications and applied PCs for People branding to donated computers
- Tested drivers and hardware for all outgoing machines
- Diagnosed and repaired computers that had been brought in with unknown issues
- Developed and maintained preseed and shell script for Linux PXE automated install
- Created network cables and organized KVMs for incoming technicians
- Performed drive wipes on hard disk drives in accordance with National Association for Information Destruction standards
- Assessed purchase needs for parts replacement
- Researched and provided accurate replacement parts order's to front desk staff for client machines

STEPHANIE MONSON

M: 715-225-0882 • 1848 St. Clair Ave. St. Paul, MN 55105 stefanimonson@gmail.com • stefanimonson.info

Business Automation Analyst (Parking and Transportation)

Mar.2014 - May 2015

Served as technical liaison for the Parking and Transportation Office with other campus departments and third-party support staff. (UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN–EAU CLAIRE ● Eau Claire, WI)

- Responsible for implementation and maintenance of all Parking Office software
- Collaborated with third-party vendors and support staff on upgrades and troubleshooting
- Created and maintained XML files and SQL business rules for import into third-party software
- Troubleshot issues, performed bug fixes, upgraded and suggested enhancements to software
- Released and deployed software and updates as required by change or office coordinator
- Created knowledge base for all Parking and Transportation software and processes
- Trained all incoming front desk staff in parking software and business rules
- Continued to perform duties from previous position in new role

Front Desk/Operations Program Associate (Parking and Transportation) Sept. 2012 – Mar. 2014
Served as lead worker in instruction and guiding front office staff in the use of the parking software and related office procedures. (UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN–EAU CLAIRE • Eau Claire, WI)

- Addressed problems or concerns through face-to-face, phone, and online communications
- Researched potential hardware/software and made recommendations to the office coordinator
- Managed parking citations, permits and accounts receivables
- Provided training to enforcement staff in the use of the handheld ticketing units
- Updated and maintained webpages using CommonSpot and AIMS software

Back Office Programmer (Point of Sale)

Jun. 2010 - Aug. 2011

Developed and maintained applications for use on departmental computers, registers and handhelds in all stores. (MENARD INC. ● Eau Claire, WI)

- Created and maintained code in both PROGRESS and Visual Basic 2006
- Created and updated business documentation for upcoming projects
- Worked with other departments to develop software for major projects
- Participated in the release and deployment process
- Continued to perform duties from previous position in new role

Back Office Programming Intern (Point of Sale)

Aug. 2008 - Jun. 2010

Developed and maintained applications for use on departmental computers in all stores. (MENARD INC. • Eau Claire, WI)

- Created and maintained programs using PROGRESS
- Designed and maintained reports to run on departmental computers and registers
- Tested systems for ease of use and error protection

EDUCATIONAL EXPERIENCE

CHIPPEWA VALLEY TECHNICAL COLLEGE ● Eau Claire, WI ● May 2010

Associate's Degree – Information Technology – Programmer/Analyst